<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Webserver | Eventually /dev/null]]></title>
  <link href="http://philnate.me/blog/categories/webserver/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://philnate.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-01T14:40:22+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://philnate.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Philipp Knobel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Stealing is bad]]></title>
    <link href="http://philnate.me/blog/2007/10/04/why-stealing-is-bad/"/>
    <updated>2007-10-04T13:42:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://philnate.me/blog/2007/10/04/why-stealing-is-bad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I never thought about such an step by myself, maybe as I never encountered such a thing upto date.<br/>
But if you run your own Webspace you should never steal any ones content or bandwidth. Then as soon as he notice it you can get some real problems, maybe he starts a lawsuite against yours(you maybe ignored some copyright laws, you caused some additional costs for him(bandwidth)). What does happen if he simply replaces the content/redirects your website to something which does harm your visitors, or does blame you?<br/>
On the Following <a href="http://wordpress.org/support/topic/96098">WordPress Topic</a> you'll can read that someone linked to some JS of Website_A. This JS is the Output of some public free available WP Plugin, the JS code even mentions that it's generated by some Plugin. But somehow the owner of Website_B was too lazy, or wanted to save some bandwidth that he simply linked to this JS file, on Website_A.<br/>
After the owner of Website_A recognized that someone was stealing his Bandwidth he created some mod_Rewrite Rule which redirected the Request from this JS to some other JS file, which contained an alertbox which appeared in front of the Visitor and told him that this Website steals some Traffic from another one. After one month the owner of Website_B discovered that JS change and removed the JS.<br/>
But it's important to say that theoretically the owner of Website_A could have written any JS code into that file. So he could steal some Cookies of the Users of Website_B or anything else he would like, he could even start some Phishing attack.<br/>
The owner of Website_B made his website vulnerable because he was to lazy to get the script itself.<br/>
Every good Webmaster/Site owner does not steal any content, as this is unethical and maybe more important dangerous!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to get PHP5 working on Debian 3.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://philnate.me/blog/2007/09/13/how-to-get-php5-working-on-debian-3-dot-1/"/>
    <updated>2007-09-13T22:28:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://philnate.me/blog/2007/09/13/how-to-get-php5-working-on-debian-3-dot-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It took me ages to get my server updated to PHP5. I've tried multiple ways to get it working as well compiling the sources itself...(Yeah I'm quite new to Linux and it's install behaves and blame me if you like, but I like the easy way not the hard one)<br/>
But I got none working except I found today that <a href="http://www.debianhelp.co.uk/apachephp5.htm">post</a>, it's quite short but it is totally enough. I've got everything I need to run my PHP now under the Version 5.<br/>
Ok it wasn't exactly as in the Post stated, I had to install as well php5-mysql, to get the database running again and I didn't needed to create softlinks to php5.conf &amp; php5.load, but it still was quite easy no need to compile the source code yourself... <br/>
With that post I'm adding as well some New Category Webserver where I take notes for everyone Public, but mostly they're for my personal usage for the case that I should need them again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
