<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: others | Eventually /dev/null]]></title>
  <link href="http://philnate.me/blog/categories/others/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://philnate.me/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-01T14:40:22+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://philnate.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Philipp Knobel]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Restoring Windows]]></title>
    <link href="http://philnate.me/blog/2007/12/05/restoring-windows/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-05T23:07:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philnate.me/blog/2007/12/05/restoring-windows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just the latest example how stupid I can be sometimes:<br/>
I've dropped yesterday my Linux Partition from my laptop. It wouldn't be that problematic if it hadn't the Boot session on it. Anyway I didn't noticed that big mistake until I restarted my Laptop and encounter some Error while Loading GRUB.<br/>
After the first seconds of thinking, what happened, I started to knock my head against the table(not really:)). As soon as I stopped to hate myself I made a search for a solution and quickly found an Answer: <a href="http://www.pcwelt.de/forum/windows-xp-server-2003/158389-grub-bootloader-gel-scht-xp-startet-2.html">Start your PC with your Recovery CD</a> and run fixmbr and fixboot. Ok, no big deal...as long as you have your Recovery CD with you, but I didn't...(second time some knocking, was hearable).<br/>
So my next try was to get some Recovery Application on the base of some small DOS Boot, I found quickly something, anyway it didn't worked for XP(at least for my PC it didn't).<br/>
Next I've inserted the Vista Recovery from some friend( I would like to mention that without any Install you can run already some Safe-Mode like Vista...with working Notepad, aso.). I was even able to start a Cmd.exe, but the next shock wasn't far as I noticed that <strong>fixmbr</strong>&amp;<strong>fixboot</strong> didn't worked within Vista. A new search was on the way, on how to get fixmbr&amp;fixboot working on Vista Recovery CDs, again I had luck and found soon, <a href="http://www.linuxforums.org/forum/installation/94066-need-fix-mbr.html">a solution</a>...you have to call them as Parameter through some other application:<br/>
<code><br/>
bootrec.exe /fixmbr<br/>
bootrec.exe /fixboot<br/>
</code><br/>
I've applied both commands, the had be done correctly and after a Restart I was able to Boot Windows again. The only good point is that I don't have to take care on startup if the correct OS is selected, anymore :).<br/>
A side note for the next time I make any changes to an OS, be sure to have the recovery CD near myself!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
